Sculpture Slide Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Sculpture Slide Collection
1960-2005
VRC 1200
Yale University Arts Library
27
160 boxes in 27 containers
Collection consists of color and black and white 35 mm slides of Western sculpture. Materials related to the Classical world are located in the Department of Classics, Phelps Hall 402, Yale University, New Haven, Connecticut, 06520.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of color and black and white 35 mm slides of Western sculpture. Materials related to the Classical world are located in the Department of Classics, Phelps Hall 402, Yale University, New Haven, Connecticut, 06520.
Arrangement
Arranged by chronological period or country.
Sculpture; Slides; Reproductions
- Egypt (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
  - General
  - Pre-Dynastic
  - Early Dynastic
    - Zoser
- Old Kingdom IV-VI (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
  - Kafre
  - Mycerinus
  - Mycerinus & Hathor & …
  - Pen-Meru Group
  - Rahotep & Nofret
  - Ranofer
  - Seated Scribe
    - Heads
    - Relief
  - 2nd Intermediate Period 13th –17th century, 1786-1750 B.C.
  - Empire or New Kingdom
    - Tomb of Tutankhamen
      - Animals
      - Colossal Figures
      - Figures
      - Heads
        - Amarna Period Heads
      - Reliefs
        - Amarna Period Reliefs
    - Abu Simbel
    - Abydos
    - Der-El-Bahri
    - Karnak
    - Medinet Abu
    - Thebes
      - Valley of the Kings
- Late Period (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
  - Dynasty 21st –25th, 1085-663 B.C.
  - Saite Period
  - Ptolemaic Period
  - Greco-Roman Period, 30th B.C.-395 A.D.
- Near East (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
  - Anatolia
  - Mesopotamia
    - Sumerian
      - Gudea
    - Babylonian
    - Assyrian
      - Relief
      - Nimrud
      - Nineveh
  - Persia
    General
    Xx for rock-cut reliefs near royal rock-cut tombs –Arch. Near East Persia- Naqsh-I-Rustem and Taq-I-Bustan
  - Syria
- Aegean (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
  - Human Figures
    - From Cyprus
    - Cyclades Figures
    - Snake Goddesses
  - Relief
  - Vessels
- Greece (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
  - General
  - Archaic c.625-480 B.C.
  - Animals
  - Figures –Female
    - "Berlin" Kore
    - Hera of Samos
    - Lady of Auxerre
    - Numbered Kore
    - Kore 670
    - Kore 674
    - Kore 675
    - Peplos Kore (679)
    - Antenor Kore (681)
    - Kore (685)
    - Euthydikos Kore (686)
    - Seated Figures
  - Figures –Male
    - Kouros from Anavyssos
    - Calf-Bearer
    - Didyma Figures
    - Kleobis & Biton
    - Metropolitan Kouros
    - Munich Kouros
    - Paros Apollo
    - Rampin Rider: Head & Figure
    - Sounion Kouros
    - Strangford Apollo
    - 'Apollo' from Tenea
    - Bronze Figures
    - Piraeus Apollo
  - Winged Figures
    - Groups
    - Heads –Female
    - Heads –Male
    - Relief
      - Various
      - Base of Kouros relief
        - Stele
        - Temples
          - Various Temples
          - Temple of Aphaia Aegina
          - Temple of Athena, Athens
        - Treasuries
          - Treasury of the Athenians
          - Treasury of the Sicyonians
          - Treasury of the Siphnians
  - Greece Classical
    - Known Artist
      - Agorakritos
      - Kephisodetos
      - Kritios
      - Lysippus
      - Myron
      - Phidias
      - Paionios of Mende
      - Polyclitus
      - Polyclitus, after (School of)
      - Praxiteles
      - Praxiteles, after (School of)
      - Scopas
    - Unknown Artist
      - Animals
      - Figures –Female
        - Various
        - Athena Figures
        - Barbarini Supplicant
        - Dying Niobid
      - Figures –Male
        - Various
        - The Charioteer of Delphi
        - Kritios Kouros
        - Marathon Boy
        - Riace Bronze Figures
          - Riace Figure A
          - Riace Figure B
        - Zeus of Artemesium
      - Groups
      - Heads –Female
      - Heads –Male
        - "Blonde Boy"
        - Heads from Tegea
      - Reliefs
        - Various
        - Balustrade of Athena Nike
        - Boston Relief
        - Mantinea Statue Base
        - Ludovisi Throne
        - Pensive Athena
        - Heroun at Gjolbaschi
        - Masoleum at Halicarnassus
        - Temple of Artemis Ephesos
        - Temple E at Selinus
        - Temple on the Ilissos
        - Temple of Zeus Olympia
          - Metopes
          - East Pediment
          - West Pediment
        - Sarcophagi
        - Stele
  - Greece Hellenistic 323-146 B.C.
    - Known Artist
      - Apollonius of Athens
      - Boethos of Chalcedon
    - Unknown Artist
      - Animals
      - Figures –Female
        - Various
        - Antium (Anzio) Girl
        - Ariadne
        - Cybele
        - Diana (Artemis) figures
        - Drunken Old Woman
        - Old Market Woman
        - Venus Figures (Aphrodite)
        - Capitoline Venus
        - Crouching Venus
        - Medici Venus
        - Venus of Melos
        - Victoria of Samonthrace
      - Figure –Male
        - Various
        - Aged Philosopher
        - Apollo Belvedere
        - Apollo from Piombino
        - Barberine Faun
        - Borghese Gladiator
        - Farnese Hercules
        - Hellenistic
        - Hemaphrodite
        - Jockey
        - Old Fisherman
        - Seated Boxer
        - Sophocles
        - Spinario
      - Groups
        - Various
        - Large Attalid Group
          - Dying Gaul
        - Small Attalid Group
        - Grotto at Sperlonga
        - Laocoon
          - Laocoon, Restoration 1
          - Laocoon Figure
          - Elder Son
          - Younger Son
          - Laocoon, Restoration 2
          - Prints and Drawings
        - Marsyas Group
        - Menelaus & Patrocles
        - Niobe & Children
      - Heads –Female
        - Various
      - Heads –Male
        - Various
        - Alexander
        - Hower
        - Pseudo-Seneca
      - Relief
        - Various
        - Pergamon
          - East Frieze
          - West Frieze
          - North Frieze
          - South Frieze
          - Telephos Frieze
      - Sarcophagi
- Iberian (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
  - Various titles
- Italic (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
  - Various titles
- Etruscan (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
  - Animals
  - Antefixes
  - Canopic Urns
  - Cinerary Urns
    - Building Types
  - Figures – Female
  - Various
  - Figures –Male
    - Various
    - Apollo of Veii
    - Mars of Todi
    - The Orator
  - Groups
  - Heads –Female
  - Heads –Male
    - Various
    - Hermes
    - Malavolta Head
    - Old Man
    - Votive Heads
  - Reliefs
    - Various
    - Grave Stele
    - Temple A at Pyrgi
    - Tomb Doors
  - Sarcophagi
    - Copenhagen Sarcophagus
    - Wedding Couple Sarco
- Roman (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
  - Animals
  - Figures -Female
    - Diana of Ephesus
    - Roman Julio-Claudian
    - Roman Severan
  - Figures –Male
    - Various
    - Roman Republic
    - Roman Augustan
      - Augustus in Toga
      - Augustus Prima Porta
    - Roman Julio-Claudi
      - Various
      - Caligula
      - Drusus (elder & Younger)
      - Tiberius
    - Roman Trajanic
    - Roman Hadrianic
    - Roman Antonine
      - Various
      - Marcus Aurelius
    - Roman Severan
    - Roman 3rd Century
    - Roman Constantinian
    - Late
  - Groups
    - Dioscuri Statues on Quirinale
    - Porphyry Emperor on Saint Mark
  - Heads
    - Various titles
    - Roman Republic
      - Various
      - Colossal Male Head
      - Capitoline Brutus
      - Julius Caesar
      - Pompey
    - Roman Augustan
      - Various
      - Augustus
    - Roman Julio-Claudian
      - Various
      - Caligula
      - Nero
    - Roman Flavian
    - Roman Trajanic
    - Roman Hadrianic
    - Roman Antonine
      - Various
      - Commodus
      - Marcus Aurelius
    - Roman Severan
      - Various
      - Julia Domna
      - Septimus Severus
      - Caracalla
    - Roman 3rd century
    - Roman Constantinian
      - Constantine (Colossal)
  - Relief
    - Various
    - Adamklessi
    - Roman Republic
      - Various
      - Altar of Ahenobarbus
      - Monument of Aemilius Paullus
    - Roman Augustan
      - Various
      - Ara Pacis
        XX for comparative figure of Aura on two-handles cup see ceramic Greece Red Figure
        - East Wall
        - North Wall
        - South Wall
        - West Wall
      - Arch at Susa
      - House under Villa Farnesina
    - Roman Julio-Claudian
      - Various
      - Ara Piatatis Augustae
      - Arch of Claudius
      - Souvetaurilia Reliefs
      - Vicomagistri Relief
    - Roman Flavian
      - Cancelleria Reliefs
    - Roman Trajanic
    - Roman Hadrianic
    - Roman Antonine
    - Roman Severan
    - Roman 3rd century
    - Roman Constantinian
  - Sarcophagi
    - Various
    - Balbinus Sarcophagus
    - Bacchic Sarcophagi
    - Battle Sarcophagi
    - Career Sarcophagi
    - Columnar Sarcophagi
    - Hunt Sarcophagi
    - Mythological Sarcophagi
      - Endymion
      - Hercules
      - Orestes
    - Season Sarcophagi
    - Wedding Sarcophagi
- Palmyra (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
- Dura-Europos (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
- Gallo Roman (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
- Romano-Britain (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
- Coptic (Transfer to the Babylonian Collection, 2008)
- Early Medieval (Box 1)
  [Slide boxes 1-6]
  - Round [Slide box 1] (Box 1)
    - 3rd century (Box 1)
    - 4th century (Box 1)
    - 5th century (Box 1)
    - 6th century (Box 1)
  - Relief (Box 1)
    - Various [Slide boxes 1-2] (Box 1)
    - 4th century [Slide box 2] (Box 1)
      - Various (Box 1)
      - Obelisk of Theodosius (Box 1)
        Xx for full view of Column see Arc. Early Medieval Constantinople Hippodrome
    - 5th century (Box 1)
    - 6th century (Box 1)
    - 7th –8th centuries (Box 1)
    - 9th –10th centuries [Slide box 3] (Box 1)
    - 11th - 12th - 13th centuries (Box 1)
      - Various (Box 1)
      - Nazareth Capitals (Box 1)
  - Sarcophagi (Box 1)
    - Various (Box 1)
    - 3rd century (Box 1)
    - 4th century (Box 1)
      - Arles Sarcophagi [Slide box 4] (Box 1)
      - Milan Sarcophagi (Box 1)
      - Rome Sarcophagi (Box 1)
        - Constantina porphyry sarcophagus (Box 1)
        - Junius Bassus Sarcophagus Vatican (Box 1)
        - Sarcophagus #174, Lateran (Box 1)
        - S. Helena Sarcophagus Vatican (Box 1)
        - Tree /Peter & Paul Sarcophagus, Lateran 164 (Box 1)
        - Trinity Sarcophagus, Lateran #104 (Box 1)
        - Two Brothers Sarcophagus, lateran 55 (Box 1)
    - 5th century (Box 1)
    - 6th century (Box 1)
- Anglo-Saxon (Box 1)
  - Various (Box 1)
  - Bewcastle (Box 1)
  - Ruthwell Cross (Box 1)
  - Sarcophagi (Box 1)
- Celtic (Box 1)
  [Slide box 5]
- Pictism (Box 1)
- Scandinavian (Box 1)
  - Various (Box 1)
  - Oserberg Ship Burial (Box 1)
- Visigothic (Box 1)
- Merovingian (Box 1)
- Carolingian (Box 1)
- Austria (Box 1)
  - Various Artists (Box 1)
  - 16th Century [Slide boxes 5-6] (Box 1)
    Xx for sculpture from the Pulkau Altar see: 3x4 Sculpture Germany XVI c.
    Xx for paintings from Pulkau Altar see: Master of Palkau (master of the Historia) painting Germany XVI c.
  - Donner, Georg Raphael, 1693-1741 [Slide box 6] (Box 1)
  - Haus-Rucker-Co. (Box 1)
  - Hausmann, Raoul, 1886-1971 (Box 1)
  - Hellmer, Edward (Box 1)
  - Knesl, Hans, 1905- (Box 1)
  - Kokoschka, Oskar, 1886- (Box 1)
  - Laib, Wolfgang (Box 1)
  - Messerschmidt, Franz X, 1736-1783 (Box 1)
  - Nitsch, Hermann, 1938- (Box 1)
  - Paalen, Wolfgang, 1905-1959 (Box 1)
  - Schiele, Egon, 1890-1918 (Box 1)
  - Soukop, Willi, 1907- (Box 1)
  - Stimm, Thomas, 1948- (Box 1)
  - Wieselthhier, Vally, 1895-1945 (Box 1)
  - Wittgenstein, Ludwig, 1889-1951 (Box 1)
  - Wotruba, Fritz, 1907- (Box 1–2)
    - Reclining Figures [Slide box 7] (Box 2)
    - Seated Figures (Box 2)
    - Standing Figures (Box 2)
    - Torsos (Box 2)
  - Zumbusch, Kaspar von, 1830-1915 (Box 2)
- Belgium (Box 2)
  - Various Artists (Box 2)
  - Bury, Pol, 1922- (Box 2)
  - Broodthaers, Marcel (Box 2)
  - Delvoye, Wim (Box 2)
  - Meunier, Constantine Emile, 1831-1905 (Box 2)
  - Minne, George, 1866-1941 (Box 2)
- Britain (Box 2)
  - Various Artists (Box 2)
    Xx for Tombs (effigies) or royalty in Westminster Abbey see Sculpture Britain 14th – 15th centuries – Colt, M., Torel, and Wm.
    Sculpture France- Jean of Liege, Sculp. Holland –Cure, C. & W. and Sculpture Italy –Torrigiano, P
  - 12th Century (Box 2)
    - Various (Box 2)
    - Baptismal Fonts (Box 2)
    - Cantherbury Choir Screen [Slide box 8] (Box 2)
  - 13th Century (Box 2)
    - Various Artists (Box 2)
    - Eleanor Crosses (Box 2)
      Xx for watercolor of Waltham Cross, as before restoration see Painting Britain-Rooker, M.A.
  - 14th Century (Box 2)
    - Various (Box 2)
  - 15th Century (Box 2)
    - Various (Box 2)
  - 16th Century (Box 2)
    - Various (Box 2)
  - 17th Century (Box 2)
    - Various (Box 2)
  - 20th Century (Box 2)
    - Adams, Robert, 1917- (Box 2)
    - Agar, Eileen, 1904- (Box 2)
    - Annesley, David, 1936- (Box 2)
    - Araee, Rasheed, 1935- (Box 2)
    - Armitage, Kenneth, 1916- (Box 2)
    - Atkinson, Conrad, 1940- [Slide box 9] (Box 2)
    - Auerbach, Arnold, 1898- (Box 2)
    - Bacon, John, 1740-1799 (Box 2)
    - Banks, Thomas, 1735-1805 (Box 2)
    - Barker, Clive, 1940- (Box 2)
    - Beckford, Franklyn, 1963 (Box 2)
    - Bedford, Richard, 1883-1967 (Box 2)
    - Ben-David, Zadok (Box 2)
    - Bickerton, Ashley, 1950- (Box 2)
    - Bird, Francis, 1667-1731 (Box 2)
    - Boyce, Sonia, 1962- (Box 2)
    - Brock, Thomas, 1847-1922 (Box 2)
    - Butler, Reginald, 1913- (Box 2)
    - Carlini, Agostino, d.1790 (Box 2)
    - Caro, Anthony, 1924- (Box 2)
    - Carrington, Leonora, 1917- (Box 2)
    - Carter, Thomas II, d.1795 (Box 2)
    - Chadwick, Helen, 1953-1996 (Box 2)
    - Chadwick, Lynn, 1914- (Box 2)
    - Chapman, Jake, 1966- (Box 2)
    - Cheere, Henry (workshop) (Box 2)
    - Cibber, Caius G. [Slide box 10] (Box 2)
      Xx Sculpture Denmark
    - Colt, Maximilian, 17th Century (Box 2)
    - Colton, William R., 1867-1921 (Box 2)
    - Cox, Stephen, 1946- (Box 2)
    - Cragg, Tony, 1949- (Box 2)
    - Cross, Dorothy, 1956- (Box 2)
    - Crozier, William, 1933- (Box 2)
    - Dalwood, Hubert, 1924-1976 (Box 2)
    - Davies, John, 1946- (Box 2)
    - Deacon, Richard, 1949- (Box 2)
    - De Monchaux, Cathy, 1960- (Box 2)
    - Dhanjal, Avtarjeet, 1936- (Box 2)
    - Dobson, Frank, 1886-1963 (Box 2)
    - Durst, Alan, 1883-1970 (Box 2)
    - Epstein, Jacob, 1880-1959 (Box 2)
    - Evans, Garth, 1934- (Box 2)
    - Fergusson, J.D, 1874-1961 (Box 2)
    - Flanagan, Barry, 1941- (Box 2)
    - Flaxman, John, 1755-1826 (Box 2)
      Xx Ceramics Britain Wedgwood
    - Ford, Onslow, 1852-1901 (Box 2)
    - Frank, Mary, 1933- (Box 2)
    - Fry, Roger, 1866-1934 (Box 2)
    - Fullard, George, 1924- (Box 2)
    - Garbe, Richard, 1876-1957 [Slide box 11] (Box 2)
    - Gertler, Mark, 1892-1939 (Box 2)
    - Gibson, John, 1790-1866 (Box 2)
    - Gilbert, Alfred, 1854-1934 (Box 2)
    - Gilbert & George (Box 2)
      Xx for Portrait of Gilbert & George by Gerhard Richter –Painting Germany- also Painting Britain
    - Gill, Eric, 1882-1940 (Box 2)
    - Gillick, Liam, 1964- (Box 2)
    - Goldsworthy, Andy, 1956- (Box 2)
    - Gordon, Douglas, 1966- (Box 2)
    - Gormley, Antony, 1950- (Box 2)
    - Hatoum, Mona, 1952- (Box 2)
    - Hepworth, Barbara, 1903-1975 (Box 2)
    - Hirst, Damien, 1965- [Slide box 12] (Box 2)
    - Househiary, Shirazeh, 1955- (Box 2)
    - Jagger, Charles S., 1885-1934 (Box 2)
    - John Wm. Goscombe, 1860-1952 (Box 2)
    - Kapoor, Anish, 1954- (Box 2)
    - Kelly, Mary, 1941- (Box 2)
    - Kennington, Eric, 1888-1960 (Box 2)
    - King, Phillip, 1934- (Box 2)
    - Lambert, Maurice, 1902-1964 (Box 2)
    - Lanyon, Peter, 1918-1964 (Box 2)
    - Latham, John, 1921- (Box 2)
    - Leighton, Frederic, baron, 1820-1896 (Box 2)
    - Lijn, Lilliane, 1939- (Box 2)
    - Lim, Kim, 1936- (Box 2)
    - Locke, Donald, 1930- (Box 2)
    - Long, Richard [Slide boxes 12-13] (Box 2–3)
    - Lord, Andrew, 1950- [Slide box 13] (Box 3)
    - Lucas, Sarah, 1962- (Box 3)
    - McClaren, Malcolm (Box 3)
    - MacKennal, Edgar Bertram, 1863-1931 (Box 3)
    - McQueen, Steve, 1966- (Box 3)
    - McWilliam, F.E., 1909- (Box 3)
    - Medalla, David, 1942- (Box 3)
    - Monro, Alexander (Box 3)
    - Moody, Ronald, 1900-1984 (Box 3)
    - Moore, Henry Spencer, 1898-1986 (Box 3)
      - Before 1929 (Box 3)
      - 1930-1935 (Box 3)
      - 1936-1939 [Slide boxes 13-14] (Box 3)
      - 1940-1949 [Slide box 14] (Box 3)
      - 1950-1959 (Box 3)
      - 1960 (Box 3)
    - Mueck, Ron, 1958- (Box 3)
    - Munro, Alexander, 1825-1871 (Box 3)
    - Nash, David, 1945- (Box 3)
    - Nato Architectural Group (Box 3)
    - Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823 (Box 3)
    - Nost, John, 1678-1729 (Box 3)
    - Oakley, Alfred, 1878-1959 (Box 3)
    - O'Donnell, Ron, 1952- (Box 3)
    - Olson, Eric, 1909- (Box 3)
    - Paolozzi, Eduardo Luigi, 1924- (Box 3)
    - Parker, Cornelia, 1956- [Slide box 15] (Box 3)
    - Pasmore, Victor, 1908- (Box 3)
    - Percy, Samuel, d.1820 (Box 3)
    - Pierce, Edward, d.1698 (Box 3)
    - Pomeroy, Frederick William, 1856-1924 (Box 3)
    - Quinn, Marc, 1964- (Box 3)
    - Reynolds-Stephens, William, 1862-1943 (Box 3)
    - Ricketts, Charles, 1866-1931 (Box 3)
    - Rolfe, Nigel (Box 3)
    - Ryan, Veronica, 1956- (Box 3)
    - Rysbrack (Box 3)
      Xx Flanders
    - Scott, Tim, 1937- (Box 3)
    - Schotz, Benno, 1891- (Box 3)
    - Shoga, Folake, 1955- (Box 3)
    - Siever, Robert William, 1794-1865 (Box 3)
    - Skeaping, John, 1901-1980 (Box 3)
    - Smith, Richard, 1931- (Box 3)
    - Thornycroft, William Hamo, 1850-1925 (Box 3)
    - Thrupp, Frederick, 1812-1895 (Box 3)
    - Toft, Albert, 1862-1949 (Box 3)
    - Torel, William, ca.1272-1291 (Box 3)
    - Tucker, William, 1935- (Box 3)
    - Turnbull, William, 1922- (Box 3)
    - Underwood, Leon, 1890-1975 (Box 3)
    - Ward, Herbert, 1863-1919 (Box 3)
    - Whiteread, Rachel, 1963- (Box 3)
    - Wilding, Alison, 1948- (Box 3)
    - Wilton, Joseph, 1722-1803 (Box 3)
    - Woodrow, Bill, 1948- (Box 3)
- Bulgaria (Box 3)
  [Slide box 16]
  - Christo, 1935- (Box 3)
    X Christo (Christo Vladimirov)
    X Christo (Javacheff)
    - Corridor—Store Front Project (Box 3)
    - The Gates (Central Park) (Box 3)
    - Mastaba of AbuDhabi (Box 3)
    - Moma Wrapped (Box 3)
    - Oil Drums (Box 3)
    - Surrounded Islands (Box 3)
    - Valley Curtain (Box 3)
    - Wrapped Coast [Slide box 17] (Box 3)
    - Wrapped Pont Neuf, Paris (Box 3)
    - Wrapped Reichstag (Box 3)
    - Wrapped Walkways, Kansa (Box 3)
- Canada (Box 3)
  - Various Artists (Box 3)
- Czechoslovakia (Box 3)
  - Various Artists (Box 3)
- Denmark (Box 3)
  - Various Artists (Box 3)
- Flanders (Box 3)
  Xx for Tournai "Marble' Baptismal Fonts, made in Flanders, for Export – Sculpture Britain XII century
  - Baerze, Jacques de, 14th – 15th Centuries (Box 3)
    Xx Retable for.. Champmol; for Paintings –Painting France Broederlam
  - Cleve, Corneille van, 1645-1732 [Slide box 18] (Box 3)
  - Duquesnoy, Francois, 1594-1643 (Box 3)
  - Dusart, Francois, ?-1661 (Box 3)
  - Renier de Huy (Box 3)
  - Rysbrack, Michael, 1693-1770 (Box 3)
    X Rysbrack, John M.
    Xx Painting Britain, Arch. Ren. Britain Stowe; for a Portrait of Rysbrack see Painting Italy- Soldi, Andrea
  - Dukes of Beaufort (Box 3)
  - Milton (Box 3)
  - Newton (Box 3)
  - Rubens (Box 3)
  - Van Dyck (Box 3)
  - William III Equestrian (Box 3)
  - Reliefs (Box 3)
  - Scheemakers, Henry, ca.1726-1748 (Box 3)
    Xx for other sculpture by Sheemakers also Arch. Ren. Britain- Stowe, Bucks
  - Scheemaeckers, Peter II, 1691-1781 (Box 3)
  - Tassaert, Jean-Pierre, 1727-1788 (Box 3)
- France (Box 4)
  [Slide box 19]
  - Romanesque (Box 4)
  - 11th Century (Box 4)
  - 12th Century (Box 4)
    - Capitals (Box 4)
    - Columns (Box 4)
    - Figures (Box 4)
    - Heads (Box 4)
    - Reliefs (Box 4)
      - Various Titles (Box 4)
        - Saint Denis (Box 4)
    - Tombs (Box 4)
    - Virgin and Child [Slide boxes 19-20] (Box 4)
  - 13th Century [Slide box 20] (Box 4)
    - Various (Box 4)
    - Heads (Box 4)
    - Tombs (Box 4)
    - Virgins, Virgin and Child (Box 4)
  - 14th Century (Box 4)
  - 15th Century (Box 4)
  - 16th Century [Slide box 20-21] (Box 4)
  - 20th Century [Slide box 21] (Box 4)
    - Various Artists (Box 4)
    - Adam, Lambert Sigisbert, 1670-1747 (Box 4)
    - Alberola, Jean-Michel, 1953- (Box 4)
    - Allegrain, Christophe-G., 1710-1795 (Box 4)
    - Allouard, Henri E., 1844-1929 (Box 4)
    - Anguir, Michel, 1612-1686 (Box 4)
    - Arman, 1920- (Box 4)
    - Arp, Hans, 1887-1966 (Box 4)
      Xx for photography of Arp see Painting France Gen., Print France, painted wood is usually classed with painting.
    - Bartholdi, Frederic A., 1834-1904 (Box 4)
    - Baschett, F. & B. (Box 4)
    - Beauneveu, Andre, 1360-1403 (Box 4)
    - Beauvallet, Pierre N., 1750-1818 [Slide box 21] (Box 4)
    - Bernard, Emil, 1868-1941 (Box 4)
    - Bertrand, Solange (Box 4)
    - Blatas, Arbit (Box 4)
    - Boiston, Joseph (Box 4)
    - Botemps, Pierre [Slide boxes 21-22] (Box 4)
    - Bouchard, Henri [Slide box 22] (Box 4)
    - Bouchardon, Edme, 1698-1762 (Box 4)
    - Bourdelle, Antoine, 1861-1929 (Box 4)
    - Bourget, Marie (Box 4)
    - Braque, Georges, 1881-1963 (Box 4)
    - Breton, Andre, 1896-1866 (Box 4)
    - Buren, Daniel, 1938- (Box 4)
    - Caffieri, Jean Jacques, 1725-1792 (Box 4)
    - Carpeaux, Jean-Baptiste, 1827-1875 (Box 4)
    - Boltanski, Christian (Box 4)
    - Carrier-Belleuse, A.E., 1824-1887 (Box 4)
    - Cayot, Claude A., 1667-1722 (Box 4)
    - Cesar Baldaccini, 1921- [Slide boxes 22-23] (Box 4)
    - Chaudet, Antonio-Denis., 1763-1810 [Slide box 23] (Box 4)
    - Chinard, Joseph, 1756-1813 (Box 4)
    - Clodion, Claude Michel, 1738-1814 (Box 4)
    - Collin-Thiebaut, G. (Box 4)
    - Colombe, Michel, 1430-1512 (Box 4)
    - Cordier, Charles-Henri-Joseph, 1827-1903 (Box 4)
    - Coustou, Guillaume I, 1677-1746 (Box 4)
    - Coustou, Nicolas, 1658-1733 (Box 4)
    - Coysevox, Antoine, 1640-1720 (Box 4)
    - Dalou, Aime-Jules, 1838-1900 (Box 4)
    - Danton, J.P., 1800-1869 (Box 4)
    - Daumier, Honore, 1808-1879 (Box 4)
    - David D'Angers, P.J., 1788-1856 (Box 4)
    - Degas, Edgar, 1834-1917 [Slide boxes 23-24] (Box 4)
    - Dejoux, Claude, 1732-1816 [Slide box 24] (Box 4)
    - Derain, Andre, 1880-1954 (Box 4)
    - Desjardins, Martin, 1636-1694 (Box 4)
    - Dubuffet, Jean, 1901- (Box 4)
    - Duchamp, Marcel, 1887-1968 (Box 4)
      Xx for Photographic material of Duchamp as Rose Selavy, his studio, etc. see Photography U.S. Man Ray.
      Xx Painting France & Prints France see Duchamp, Marcel
      Xx Miscellaneous Movements see Dada & Surrealism, for portrait of Duchamp see painting France Crotti, Jean
      - Assemblages/Associated Works (Box 4)
        - Large Glass [Slide box 24-25] (Box 4–5)
        - Box in the Valise [Slide box 25] (Box 5)
        - Given… Étant Donnés… (Box 5)
        - Dust Breeding (Box 5)
        - Glider and Water Mill (Box 5)
        - Green Box (Box 5)
        - Malic Molds (Box 5)
        - Standard Stoppages (Box 5)
      - Erotica (Box 5)
      - Optics (Box 5)
        - Anémic Cinema (Box 5)
      - Ready-Mades (Box 5)
        - Various (Box 5)
      - Bicycle Wheel (Box 5)
        - Bottle Dryer (Box 5)
      - Clothing (Box 5)
        - Fountain (Box 5)
        - In Advance of the Broken Arm [Slide box 26] (Box 5)
      - Trap (Box 5)
        - Why Not Sneeze… (Box 5)
      - Surrealist Exhibition (Box 5)
    - Duchamp-Villon, Raymond, 1876-1918 (Box 5)
      - New York (Box 5)